Whitney Crawford

Savannah, GA 31406

Phone: 843-830-2110 | **Email:** whitneylcrawford@gmail.com **LinkedIn:** www.linkedin.com/in/whitney-lee-crawford

Summary

Experienced educator and certified Full Stack Web Developer. Exceptional communication and presentation skills, including facilitating trainings and professional development. Efficient in overseeing and organizing large scale events such as Jump Rope for Heart, overnight trips, and graduation. Proficient in both frontend and backend web languages as well as CMS libraries. Fitness enthusiast and long-time participant in running events throughout Savannah and the Lowcountry.

Experience

Web Developer 2019-present Freelance Savannah, GA

Build, design, and deploy websites from scratch or utilizing frontend frameworks such as Bootstrap. *Key Accomplishments:*

- My application, MenYou, was nominated by Trilogy Education Services as a finalist for the Next Level Contest.
- Member of the Google Developers Group of Savannah
- Presenter at Georgia Tech's Demo Day

Fifth Grade Teacher

Charleston County/Hancock Day School

Charleston, SC/Savannah, GA

2005-2019

Taught hundreds of students on best practices to approach problem solving methodically and reach a solution. Managed grade level for 11 years and lead faculty trainings as well as mentored new employees. *Key Accomplishments:*

- Recognized as Teacher of the Year for strong leadership.
- Nominated as a Master Teacher for involvement in youth activities and excellence in fostering positive relationships in the community.
- Coached cheerleading, cross country, track and field, and mentored pre-teen girls through the non-profit program known as Girls on the Run.

Certified Trainer 2009-2012 SMART Technologies Charleston,SC

Demonstrated SMARTboard products designed to enhance student interactions and improve learning. Led a 6 week course on how to use software features and design engaging lessons for the classroom.

Education

Full Stack Coding Boot Camp Georgia Tech

02/2019-08/2019 Savannah, GA

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML, CSS, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS

Bachelor of Science in Elementary Education

2000-2005

College of Charleston

Charleston, SC

Certified by the State of South Carolina and Georgia to teach grades 2-6, Highly Qualified